As you are moving around between apps, you probably notice that from a user
perspective, Android doesn't announce changes in app state. It doesn't announce,
that it's low in memory or ask users to close apps, to free up resources. In
fact, it does everything it can, to make the resource limitation to the device,
invisible to the user. That means keeping the foreground app running smoothly,
and switching between apps seamless, and that means killing apps in
the background. And it does that if it
needs their resources to make sure that the foreground apps can continue to run.
So we know that as soon as your app isn't visible, its lifetime is as
perilous as that of a Stark at the Red Wedding. Likely to die without notice,
but ready to return from the dead. That tells us some very important things
about how our app should behave to be good citizens and provide a great user
experience. From a system perspective, on pause and on stop are signals that our
app may be killed eminently. So we need to clean up any resources that
need an orderly tear down such as closing any open connections or sockets.